Paulius Maciukevičius

SUMMARY

All experience is in Fintech, Telcom companies. Extensive knowledge of Java 7, 8, 11 Spring Boot framework and Micro service architecture and integration with other 3rd party API's. (JPA, Hibernate, Web, REST API's, stateless services, MVC, Junit4), good understanding of JavaScript React (NEXTJS). Experience in working in Agile setup with participation in all ceremonies and also their facilitation and 4+ years of work experience.

SKILLS

Java,
Spring Boot (Security,Rest, Batch,
Web...)
Spring MVC (Wicket, Jsp)
JavaScript (Next.js, React)
Java integration with databases
PostgreSQL, Oracle (PL/SQL),
MongoDB, MongoDB cloud

Docker

Deployment and scaling management (Heroku, Vercel, Openshift, Github Actions, Github Organization) also packaging and deploying to internal linux servers. Experience preparing code deployments to testing and productions environments.

Codebase interactions (Tortoise SVN, GitHub, Bitbucket)
Testing (Junit, Snyk, Sonarqube(Cloud))
Dependency management (
Maven, Gradle, Npm)
Functional testing (Postman API)
IntelliJ IDEA as a main development tool
Documentation (Swagger, OpenApi)

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Programming in JAVA, Object Oriented Programming, Programming Design principles, Relational and NoSQL databases, Spring Framework

Java Programming

CODEACADEMY (2018)

CODEACADEMY (2017)

LANGUAGES

NATIVE / BILINGUAL LITHUANIAN

PROFESSIONAL WORKING PROFICIENCY ENGLISH

PROFESSIONAL WORKING PROFICIENCY RUSSIAN

EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2023 ADDENDUM PRO

FULL-STACK JAVA DEVELOPER

- Collaboration with the team and testers, analysis and goal orientated solutions.
- Developed applications Kotlin/JAVA in microservice infrastructure and monolithic approaches.
- Junit/Sonarqube, integration and functional testing.
- PI/SQL. Experience refactoring and maintaining old code.
- Front End with MVC framework also JavaScript(React, Next.js).
- Integrated xml templates to send and receive data between international banks.
- Created microservice applications to separate functionalities.
- Deployment pipelines configurations with Openshift and Jenkins.
- Consulted product owners, analysts and other personnel on best solutions for business logic.

Tech. stack: Java, Kotlin Spring, REST, JavaScript (Next.Js, React), SEO (beginner) Oracle (PL/SQL), GIT, Gradle, IntelliJ IDEA, Linux, JUnit, Sonarqube, xml, Openshift, Jenkins, yaml.

2019-2021 SEB Nordic Bank JAVA DEVELOPER

- Performed application integration with external systems using Restful services.
- Developed REST web services to facilitate communication between client and servers.
- Leveraged GIT and Tortoise SVN for version control, and Maven and Spring Boot for project build.
- Used Maven for building the project wars as well as deploying to development environments.
- Used Postman for testing in development environment, bug reporting and fixing.
- Deployed applications to Linux environments (for staging and production).

Tech. stack: Java, Spring boot, Hibernate, Maven, REST, JSON, xml, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Swagger, Mercurial, Git, Tortoise SVN, IntelliJ IDEA, CSS, HTML, Wicket, JavaScript, RabbitMQ, Openshift, Jenkins.

2017-2018 TELCO **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

- New Prepaid subscribers' services implementation.
- Existing prepaid services monitoring / modification / customization and bug fixing.
- Middleware services implementation, testing. Debugging and bug fixing.
- Customer services monitoring (staging and production environment).
- Various procedures optimization and stabilization.
- Automated processes job creation and monitoring.

Tech. stack: JAVA, Spring Batch, Oracle, Redis, SQL, NoSQL DB Linux (winscp, putty, postman), Zabbix.